[Encapsulated Reality | Divine Poetry]
[Realtà Incapsulata | Poesia Divina]
Kṛṣṇa is siddhānta.
Kṛṣṇa è il siddhānta.
They're not two separate things.
Non sono due cose separate.
Kṛṣṇa is siddhānta, siddhānta is Kṛṣṇa.
Kṛṣṇa è il siddhānta. Il siddhānta è Kṛṣṇa.
The ślokas are encapsulated reality;
Questi śloka sono realtà incapsulata.
they're real, they're alive, they're living,
Sono reali, sono vivi, sono vitali,
they're streaming real-time Kṛṣṇa conception.
da essi sgorga in tempo reale la concezione di Kṛṣṇa.
So Śrīla Gurudev, he liked so much
A Śrīla Gurudev piace molto
the one verse from Gītā-govinda
un verso della Gītā-govinda
that appears somewhat in Charitāmṛtam.
che compare da qualche parte nel Charitāmṛtam,
He liked to sing it sometimes. Like he told—what did he say?
gli piaceva cantarla qualche volta,
Manasa Krishna told, Gurudev said, "Good for hearing but not for telling",
come diceva lui: "Buono da ascoltare, ma non da dire".
like not explaining.
cioè non da spiegare.
But it's very beautiful, and it's mentioned that
Ma è molto bello e si dice che
when Mahāprabhu would hear this He would faint.
quando Mahāprabhu lo ascoltava sveniva.
lalita-lavañga-lata-pariśīlana-komala-malaya-samīre
lalita-lavañga-lata-pariśīlana-komala-malaya-samīre
madhukara-nikara-karambita-kokila-kūjita-kuñja-kutīre (Gītā-govinda: 1.4)
madhukara-nikara-karambita-kokila-kūjita-kuñja-kutīre (Gītā-govinda: 1.4)
So the beauty, as given by Jayadev Goswāmī,
Allora la bellezza, com'è data da Jayadev Goswāmī,
if you listen, the la-la-la-la-la, ka-ka-ka-ka-ka.
nel la-la-la, ka-ka-ka,
lalita-lavañga-lata-pariśīlana-komala-malaya-samīre
lalita-lavañga-lata-pariśīlana-komala-malaya-samīre
madhukara-nikara-karambita-kokila-kūjita-kuñja-kutīre
madhukara-nikara-karambita-kokila-kūjita-kuñja-kutīre,
This is divine sound and divine poetry,
questo è suono divino e divina poesia,
describing the beauty of Kṛṣṇa and the Pastimes of Kṛṣṇa.
che descrive la bellezza di Kṛṣṇa e i Passatempi di Kṛṣṇa.